It's just curious whether this kind of process in larger view code
basis kind of results in the constants type strip file,
getting kind of cannibalized or incorporated into the types file.
Do you see frequently constants files?
So yeah.
So this is a great question.
Because let's take a look at this.
And this segway is perfectly, instead of next thing
I wanted to talk about.
So here we've noticed that we have our constants types here.
And we also have our types here.
And as developers, we have been inundated
with the do not repeat yourself rule, which,
to me, is often done overkill.
But obviously, we can see here that there's some duplication.
We have two sources of truth.
This is a bit of a problem.
So the thing about the constants being
subsumed in the types though, is that the constants
are still valid JavaScript like values
that you could assign later on.
So for example, what one of the things we're about to do
is if we take a look at our application
and if we go to new restaurant, you'll notice
we're actually not rendering out the status right now.
There's no way for users to pick which status it is.
And so when you do that, which we'll do in a little bit,
we'll want to import this constant as an array that
will loop through and then render out our options.
But remember that the value here is not the same as a type,
because this type can never be consumed
in a way that traditional JavaScript would.
And so let's go ahead and see how we would solve that problem.
Because this is a common one.
So let me start by showing the problem
and then we'll go from here.
So what we're going to try to do right now
is inside a restaurant, the new restaurant page,
we're going to go ahead and flush this part out.
So I'm going to go ahead and go into new restaurant.
And we can see here that this hasn't been moved over
the type trip yet.
So I'm going to go ahead and do that.
Let's say set up Lang TS.
And then after that, we're going to,
oh, you know what?
I'm not going to do that just yet,
because I want to prove something real quick.
OK, I'll just do it to Lang TS.
And then I'll import Define Component from view.
And so actually just to explain what I'm thinking here.
The reason we're not going to do this group set up just yet
is because I haven't taught you all how to define
and myths and props and that kind of stuff.
So rather than skip directly to that,
we're just going to use something we're familiar with,
which is the Define Component.
OK.
So here inside of, let's see, where's our status?
Ah, status is right here.
You'll notice that it's looking for this restaurant status list.
It doesn't exist right now.
And the reason for that is we haven't imported yet.
So if I import restaurant status list from my constants,
I can actually ingest it here inside of my reactive data.
And then once I do that, you'll see that everything shows up.
But we serve a small problem here.
And the reason for that is because we
have this duplication of data.
And so the question is, is there a way for TypeScript
to look at a constant we define here and then generate the types
from it?
And so how this works, I honestly don't know why they designed it
this way.
But it's fine.
I'll show you how it works.
All right, the first thing you're going to do when you want,
because because, OK, think of it this way.
What you kind of want in, like, if we were to do this ourselves,
is we kind of want to be like loop through restaurant list,
status list, constant, and then unite them with a union operator.
We were programmatically agent.
Kind of what we're thinking.
So you might be thinking, oh, there's a four loop or something.
Not quite.
The way this works is first, let's go ahead and import our constant.
So we'll import restaurant, let's say,
restaurant, OK, it doesn't like the imports,
so I'll just have to manually do it constants.
OK.
So if I do restaurant, why is it not like it?
Status?
It does not like it.
Import type unresolved.
Oh, oh, sure.
OK, yeah, that's OK.
Sorry, this error is correct.
This is not going to work, right?
Because this is a JavaScript value.
This is not a type, right?
We have a keyword for that for a reason.
So one thing you can do, or what you're supposed to do,
the most popular convention, is you type-casted as a constant.
And this is my number one complaint.
Because it is already a constant.
It's weird to me that you would type something as a constant.
But you'll notice it does something though,
to the restaurant status list, is that it makes it
available to type-ative as this read-only tuple.
And so for those that aren't familiar with that programming term,
it's basically where you have an array with fixed values in certain positions.
Although, I'm not saying it is a tuple, but it's just kind of like that.
Where it's saying, these are arrays with these specific values in these specific places.
And then, don't care for this in text.
I'm just making this for the record.
You ask for the type of the restaurant status list.
And then, not only that, you have to then use this square bracket number,
because it is technically an array of things you're reading.
But arrays are accessed via a number.
Like, this number here is not arbitrary.
It is the type of value that's being used to access the values inside
of this read-only thing.
But once you do this though, you will notice that type status is actually
generating as you would expect.
It has a want to try or, and so now, if we come in here and we're like,
hey, we want to add a delicious, like, and we save it.
Cool.
Status is automatically updated.